<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class name="FmodSoundLock" inherits="RefCounted" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/godotengine/godot/master/doc/class.xsd">
	<brief_description>
		Provides direct access to sound sample data for reading or modification.
	</brief_description>
	<description>
		FmodSoundLock is used to lock a region of sound data for direct access. This allows reading or modifying the raw sample data of a sound.
		When a sound is locked, FMOD provides one or two pointers to the data (two pointers are used if the locked region wraps around the end of the sound buffer).
		[b]Important:[/b] Always call [method unlock] when finished accessing the data, or use the RAII pattern (let the object go out of scope) to automatically unlock.
		[b]Note:[/b] Locking a sound may be expensive as it can block the mixer thread. Use sparingly and for short durations.
	</description>
	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>
	<methods>
		<method name="get_data1" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="PackedByteArray" />
			<description>
				Returns the first portion of locked data as a byte array.
				This contains the majority of the locked region in most cases.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_data2" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="PackedByteArray" />
			<description>
				Returns the second portion of locked data as a byte array.
				This is only non-empty when the locked region wraps around the end of the sound buffer.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="is_locked" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="bool" />
			<description>
				Returns [code]true[/code] if the sound data is currently locked and accessible.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="unlock">
			<return type="void" />
			<description>
				Unlocks the sound data, allowing FMOD to resume normal processing.
				This should be called as soon as you're finished accessing the data.
				The destructor automatically calls this if the data is still locked.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
</class>
